<form stylesheet="Help.css,Home.css,hover.css,hide_timeindicator.css">
  <label>Help</label>
  <row>
    <html>

		<br />

		<div class="round-button">
			<a href="Home">
			<img src="../../static/app/iptables/icons/Home_Icon.svg" alt="Home"/>
			</a>
		</div>

      <div style="text-align: center;">
        <img src="../../static/app/iptables/logos/netfilter.png"/>
      </div>
      
      <div class="logosubtitle">        
        <h2>Netfilter Iptables</h2>
		</div>

		<br />
		<br />

    </html>
  </row>
  <row>
    <html>


<p>Copyright 2014-2017 Guilhem Marchand	<br />

	<br />
   Licensed under the Creative Common V3.0
	<br />
	<br />   
   
   <a target="_blank" href="http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/">http://creativecommons.org/licenses/by/3.0/</a>
   
   <br />
   <br />

	
<b>Netfilter Iptables release 3.2.0</b>

<br />

<br />

<a href="../../static/app/iptables/releases-note.txt">See Releases Notes</a>

</p>

	</html>
  </row>
  <row>
    <html>
	 
<h1>Welcome in Netfilter Iptables for Splunk, IP Firewall for Linux Systems</h1>

<br />

<h2>TABLE OF CONTENT</h2>

<ol>

<li>INTRODUCTION</li>
<li>PREREQUISITES</li>
<li>INSTALLATION</li>
<li>UPGRADE INSTRUCTIONS</li>

</ol>
	 

	</html>
  </row>
  
  
  <row>
    <html>	

		<h1>1. INTRODUCTION</h1>

		<br />
		
		The Netfilter Iptables Application for Splunk intends to exploit Iptables logs generated by Linux based systems to provide main Network informations.
		
		<br />
		<br />
		
		Associated with Splunk's power, the App provides a nice frontend for Iptables and will offer you the global knowledge of your Network Activity.
		
		<br /> 

	 </html>

	</row>


  <row>
    <html>	

		<h1>2. PREREQUISITES</h1>

		<br />
		
		Only internal Splunk modules are being used, the Netfilter Iptables App has no requirements but Splunk 6.1 as the minimal version
		
		<br />

	 </html>

  </row>
	
	
	
  <row>
    <html>	

		<h1>3. INSTALLATION</h1>

		<br />
		
		<b>The Application intends to index Iptables Syslog events in the Splunk data index:</b>
		
		<br />
		
		<lu>
		
		<br />		
		
		<li>iptables_index</li>
		
		</lu>
		
		<br />		
		
		<b>Events identifications are associated with the sourcetype configuration contained in:</b>
		
		<br />		
		
		<lu>
		
		<br />		
		
		<li>iptables_source</li>
		
		</lu>
		
		<br />
		
		<b>For more simplicity, i would advise configuring your system to generate a dedicated Iptables log file which only contain Iptables events.</b>
		
		<br />
		<br />

		This can be achieved with simple configuration in the host syslog system, configuration samples are provided above		
		
		<br />
		<br />		

		<b>If you intend to have multiple hosts, then you have multiple solutions:</b>

		<br />
		
		<lu>
		
		<br />		
		
		<li>Using Splunk Forwarders with a minimal configuration to send events to your Splunk indexers</li>
		
		<br />
		
		<li>Using a syslog centalized system that will receive events from remote hosts and store them in files that will be indexed by Splunk</li>
		
		</lu>

		<br />		
		<br />

	 </html>

	</row>


  <row>
    <html>	

		<h1>3. UPGRADE INSTRUCTIONS</h1>

		<br />
		
		<b>Upgrading the Application is very simple and shall be done through the standard Splunk procedure, you may proceed as following:</b>
		
		<br />
		
		<lu>
		
		<br />
		
		<li>Through the Application Management, when an update has been detected by Splunk, follow the update link and update the App</li>
		
		<br />
		
		<li>Download the new App version from Splunk Base, open the App management and update the Application</li>
		
		<br />
		
		<li>Download the new App version file, and untar it manaually to $SPLUNK_HOME/etc/apps</li>
		
		</lu>
			
		<br />

	 </html>

  </row>


</form>